- [Voiceover] When it comes time
to pick out and purchase a computer,
one of the first decisions
you'll have to make
is whether you want to
get a desktop computer,
a laptop computer or
even a tablet computer.
Here's an example of a laptop computer.
Laptop computers are also often
called notebook computers.
These computers are
designed for portability,
often weighing less
than four or five pounds
and they have the monitor, keyboard
and mouse pointing device built in
so you usually don't have
to plug in other accessories
to use the computer.
And these are examples
of desktop computers.
Now, the term desktop can mean
different things when you're
talking about computers
but in this context, desktop refers to
all computers that
either sit on or next to
your desk or work station.
The computer itself does not have a
built-in monitor, keyboard or mouse
but the keyboard and
mouse are usually included
in the same box the computer ships in
and the have to be
plugged in to the computer
when you set it up.
And desktop computers are not designed
to be portable or carried around a lot.
But how do you decide which
type of computer to get?
Well for the most part,
you should only select
a laptop if you genuinely
need the portability.
Laptops today are nearly
if not just as powerful
as their deskptop counterparts,
but you'll usually be
spending more money on laptops
for the same amount of power
you can get from a desktop computer.
Desktop computers also have the advantage
of being more upgradable.
Yes, laptops have USB ports
for adding external hard drives
but desktop computers usually have
more available USB
ports and they also have
slots for expansion cards or for
additional internal hard
drives or optical drives.
Desktops are usually easier
to upgrade yourself too.
Also if your computer is
mainly going to be used
in your home or office and you
don't need the portability,
you can treat yourself
to a much larger monitor
than you would get on the laptop.
Laptop displays generally
top out around 17 inches
but these days you can purchase montitors
at 23, 27 or even 30
inch and larger sizes.
Of course many laptops offer the ability
to connect to additional
monitors these days too,
but you're still going to be paying more,
so unless you really need the portability,
you'll want to stick with the desktop model.
Now you've probably heard
of a third type of computer
called a tablet computer.
Devices like Apple iPads
and Android tablets
fall under this category.
They come with touch screen displays
and you operate them
by touching and tapping
the screen with your fingers.
However, I wouldn't recommend the iPad
or an Android device
as your only computer.
They're not nearly as powerful or capable
of doing professional work, and they run
a different operating system than is found
on desktop and notebook computers.
However, if you're interested in a tablet
but also want the power and capability
of a desktop operating system,
another category of computer to consider
is the hybrid computer.
This includes computers like the
Microsoft Surface Pro 4,
which is a touch screen tablet
that runs the same version of
the Windows operating system found on
desktop and notebook computers.
So you can operate it
with just your fingers,
or you can attach a keyboard to it
to make it more like a notebook computer.
But just like with a notebook computer
if you don't need the portability,
you'll probably want to consider
getting a desktop computer.
And again, while tablet computers are
great devices to have, and you can do
all kinds of work on them from
word processing to video editing,
at this point for most people
I don't think they're suitable
to be the only computer in
your office or household
and throughout the rest of the course,
I'll be working on the assumption
that you either have a desktop
or a notebook computer.