In this demonstration we will
troubleshoot broken computer connections
usually a client will establish a secure
channel to the domain controller and
authenticate to the domain
however sometimes the computer cannot
establish a connection and this is
referred to as a broken channel there are
number of reasons this can occur perhaps
you recently installed the operating
system and the security ids are different
or maybe the computer has been inactive
for a long period of time or the account
has been reset
either way the account exists and the
client cannot authenticate to the domain
the symptoms of a broken channel are
very clear here we have Meghan who is
reported to the help desk that when she
tries to login she gets an error message
the trust relationship between this
workstation and the primary domain
failed once you recognize you have a
broken channel you'll want to log into
the computer as the domain administrator
and then under system properties you
want to change the computer from the
domain to a temporary work group and you
will need the local administrator
account to get back on
once you're welcomed to the temporary
work group you'll be prompted to restart
the computer after the machine restarts
you'll need to login as the local admin
because you're not on the domain and
then return to system properties and
change from the workgroup back to the
domain and you will need administrator
credentials to get onto the network and
you'll also need to restart the machine
after the computer restarts Meghan will
be able to join the domain and you'll be
able to close the ticket so remember
when you have a broken channel remove
the computer from the domain and then
rejoin it and your course does have a
lab on this so please take a few minutes
to give it a try.