In this demonstration we will look at
configuring Group Policy preferences
now we'll start in Server Manager under
the Tools menu with Group Policy
management and within group policy
management we will expand the forest and
the domain and then edit the Default
Domain Policy for adatam.com now in the
Group Policy Management Editor both
Computer Configuration and User
Configuration have Preferences and
within Preferences there are Windows
Settings and Control Panel Settings
let's take a look at some of the things
you can do with the Windows Setting
Preferences you can map a network share
or folder you can limit registry
options or settings you can create a
shortcut to the desktop file system or
URL and you can create a folder or set
of nested folders and that's what we'll
do we'll go over to Windows Settings and
on Folders right-click and select New
Folder and on the drop-down on this page
we're going to select as our action
Create and this will be a folder on the
c drive for the Research group we could
do something fancier but we'll keep it
simple
now on the Common tab it's important to
remember that preferences are always
reapplied but there is an option to
change that one thing that unique about
Preferences is Item Level Targeting item
level targeting lets you specify exactly
where to apply the preference so you can
apply it to particular computers or an
IP address range an organizational unit
a user you can even specify the
operating system that you want to apply
this to now we're going to keep it
simple and choose the Research
organizational unit but know that you
can combine different criteria to target
a very specific set of items once the
preference is created we apply our
changes and then click OK make sure the
preferences were created and then
if we want to push these changes out we
can use GPupdate  / force just
like you do with group policy and it'll
just take a minute or so before it
reports back that this is completed
successfully
once that happens we're ready to test so
I'll switch over to the client computer
and I'll log in as Rose Rose is a member
of the Research group so after she's
logged in we should be able to navigate
to the c drive and there should be a
research folder that has been created in
summary your preferences are different
from policies they are not enforced and
they provide item level targeting now
your course does have a lab on Group
Policy preferences so please take a few
minutes to give it a try.