In this demonstration we will look at
creating and nesting groups when it
comes to implementing group management
in the domain you need a strategy begin
by identifying the different identities
in the organization like sales managers
and auditors next collect those
identities into global groups based on
the members role for example a sales
global group and an auditors global
group now when you need to provide
access the domain resources consolidate
the global groups into a domain local
group for example you can add the sales
and auditors global groups into a single
domain local group called sales and
auditors lastly assign your domain local
group to the resources for example a
folder and then create permissions on
that resource this best practice for
nesting groups is known by the acronym
IGDLA let's look at how to implement
this practice here in Server Manager
under the Tools menu lets select the
Active Directory Administrative Center
and in the ADAC we can right-click the
domain and select new group now the
first group that we will create is
called auditors and it will be a
security group and the group scope will
be global now global groups are
primarily used to consolidate users who
have similar characteristics like
auditors
let's add another group this group will
be called sales and auditors and this
will be a security group and the group
scope will be domain local now let's add
for the members tab the sales group and
the auditors group we now have a group
that we could assign to protected
documents on a shared network resource
so you want to use domain local groups
to manage access to resources or to
assign management rights
now if you prefer you can use the
Windows PowerShell History to see the
commands that you could use for example
the New-ADGroup would create a
group scope of global for the auditors
group and then the second group we
created the group scope is domain local
and that's for your sales and auditors
group and then Set-ADGroup can be
used to add members to a group like we
did with the sales and auditor groups
your course does have labs on managing
group accounts so be sure to take a few
minutes and give those a try.