- [Voiceover] When using
the word, computer,
in the context of this training course,
I'm referring to the entire package
of everything you need to
actually accomplish tasks.
So people refer to a computer as just
the actual unit housing
the main components
of the hard drive,
processor, memory and so on.
But to use a computer, you also need
a monitor, so you can
see what you're doing.
Some computers like notebook computers
or all-in-one computers
have built-in monitors
but it's important to
not confuse the monitor
with the computer itself.
The monitor is also called the display
and it's doesn't do any
of the work or processing.
It simply displays the
computer's interface
which is still an essential component
of the entire system.
You also need a keyboard and a mouse
so you can enter text and commands
and control the computer.
You often need speakers or headphones
so you can hear the sounds
your computer makes.
Some computers have built-in speakers
while others don't.
Computers also need to
have an operating system,
which is the software that manages
the operation of the entire system.
We'll talk more about operating
systems a little bit later.
And to use a computer you'll
also need applications,
which are the programs
that run on your computer
like word processsing,
spreadsheet or photo editing applications.
Many computers come with built-in software
and you can purchase and install thousands
of other software applications
you might want or need.
You may also need additional hardware
to have your computer perform other tasks.
For example, you'll need a printer,
in order to have paper
copies of your documents.
Or a scanner to create electronic versions
of your paper documents.
These days, your printer and scanner, may,
in fact, be the same device though.
And if you want to get online,
you'll also need Web-browsing software,
a modem and to subscribe
to an Internet service
if you want to get on the
Web with your computer.
So, at the very least, you need the
computer unit itself, a monitor,
an operating system and the keyboard
and mouse to have a computer system.
But all of these things and more make up
your computer system and generally,
when we talk about computers,
we're talking about any configuration
that involves these basic
and essential components.