In this demonstration we'll look at a
common administrator task managing
password policies now password policies
are defined through group management so
let's begin in Server Manager under the
Tools menu selecting Group Policy
Management and then we're going to edit
the default domain policy for Adatum.com
in the group policy management
editor the settings that we're looking
for are under computer configuration
policies windows settings security
settings and then under security
settings account policies and there are
two policies we're going to look at
password policy and account lockout
policy
let's begin with the password policy
settings you can specify when a user can
reuse a password from their password
history you can set the number of days a
password can be used before the user
must change it and you can set the
minimum number of characters the
password must contain there are also
password complexity requirements and if
you're not sure what a particular
setting is just open the setting and the
explain tab will provide some additional
information in this case the password
cannot contain the user's account name
or parts of the users full name
also important are the account lockout
policies the account lockout threshold
determines the number of failed login
attempts before a user is locked out the
default value of zero indicates a user
will never be locked out
you want to set this value high enough
to allow for mistyped passwords but low
enough to protect against brute force
attempts to guess the password these
global settings are applied to the
domain but what if you would like a
particular group to have a different set
of password settings to do this will
return to server manager the tools menu
and select the active directory
administrative center now in the global
search text box I'll type in password
settings
this is a nice administrator trick
what's returned is the password settings
container and on the right I can then
set up a new set of password settings
now these settings should look familiar
but what's different is on the bottom
right I can add a group or groups for
this particular set of settings so I can
specify these settings are for my domain
admins and then I can require my domain
admins to have a longer password I can
shorten the password history
and I can make them change their
password more often after adding a name
and a precedence I will have a set of
settings just for my domain admins these
types of passwords are often referred to
as fine-grained passwords your course
has several labs on password management
please take a few minutes to try them.