In this demonstration we will use a user
template to create a new user and we'll
start in Server Manager under the Tools
menu with the Active Directory Users and
Computers tool now in the sales
organizational unit we've already
created a template and most employees
start with an underscore so that they
appear at the top of the list and they are
easily recognizable now if we look at
the properties on this template then we
can see some things have already been
filled out for us
for example the description the office
on the organization tab we have the
Department sales the company Adatum and
the manager Adam Hobbs and on the member
of tab you can see we've added this
member to the sales group to save time
you want to fill out as many attributes
as you can now to create a user from our
template simply right-click the template
and select copy
in the copy object page that comes up
you'll provide the user a name including
a user login name
the user will also need a password
and that's it
now if we take a look at our new user we
can see some things have already been
filled out for us under account the city
information is there
under organization we see Department
company name of the manager and this
person is a member of the sales group
remember some things are not copied your
organization may need multiple templates
but using templates will not only save
you time it will ensure that the
attributes for each user are consistently entered.