This demonstration will look at a common
administrator task create user account
and will start in server manager under
the Tools menu with the active directory
administrative center in the ADAC just
right-click the domain of interest then
select new and user every user in your
domain must have a user account and you
should never let users share accounts
now in the create user page there is only two
pieces of information that are required
full name and login name the full name
is a combination of first name and last
name for the login information you want
to make sure if you have a large number
of users that it's easily recognizable
and it is unique and then every user who
logs in the first time will need a
password so you can provide a password
for the user on the right-hand side make
sure user must change password at next
login is selected and if this was a
temporary hire you can also specify
the hours they could login or the
computers they can log on to there's a
lot of other information about your user
you can provide on the organization tab
and the more information you provide the
better
there's the office that they work in
their email address their job title
the department that they work in there's
a lot of contact information and if you
have a large number of users that share
the same attributes you definitely want
to consider using a user template that
you can create each user from user
templates are covered in your course
materials now if you prefer you can use
the ADAC history to show you the
PowerShell commands the first one is
New-ADUser this is where you set all
the attributes for the user and then
you'll use Set-ADAccountPassword
to give the user that initial password
and the third command you need is
Enable-ADAccount so whether you use the a
deck or Powershell that's all you need
to create a user.